themeenergy.com 2019-05-26

# Privacy Policy – Premium WordPress Themes & HTML Templates | ThemeEnergy

## Introduction

Hi, we’re ThemeEnergy (“themeenergy,” “we,” or “us”) and welcome to our privacy policy. We are an EU based company, creating products that enhance your online presence.  
This policy sets out how we handle your personal information if you’re a user of our WordPress themes, HTML templates or visitor to our Sites. 

Please read our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy, providing consent to both documents in order to have permission to use our services. They apply across themeenergy.com, our demo websites and ThemeEnergy Support Desk.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it?

We collect certain personal information about visitors and users of our Sites.

## How we collect personal information

We may collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, automatically as you navigate through the Sites or when you use services associated with the Sites.

When you provide personal information to us via the Sites you’re consenting to us collecting and using that information in line with this policy and the user terms of each of the Sites.

### Registration Data

If you register on our Sites, we store your chosen username and your email address and any additional personal information added to your user profile. You can see, edit, or delete your personal information at any time (except changing your username). Website administrators can also see and edit this information.

### Purchase Data

To receive product support, you have to register one or more Envato purchase codes on our site. These purchase codes will be stored together with support expiration dates and your user data. This is required for us to provide you with downloads, product support and other customer services.

### Support Data

If you have registered on our Sites and have a valid support account, you can submit support tickets for assistance. Support form submissions are sent to our third party Ticksy ticketing system. Only the data you explicitly provided is sent. Ticksy also adheres to the EU/US “Privacy Shield” and you can see their privacy policy here: [Ticksy Privacy Policy](https://ticksy.com/privacy-policy/).

### IP address

We collect the IP addresses of visitors and users this website. We will use this information to improve our themes by adding language-specific features to them, providing location-specific social media posts, tutorials, promotions, as well as improving security.

### Google analytics

We use Google Analytics on our site for anonymous reporting of site usage. So, no personalized data is stored. If you would like to opt-out of Google Analytics monitoring your behavior on our site please use this link: [Google Analytics Opt-out/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

### Newsletter and email activity

Through Mailchimp we monitor your email activity; which of our newsletters/emails campaign, you open and which of them you click. This reflects our users’ account about our newsletter and helps us to include more useful and relevant content in our emails.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Cookies

This site uses cookies – small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymized tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. Cookies generally exist to make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the help section of your browser.

## Who we share your data with

If you are not a registered client for our site, there is no personal information we can retain or view regarding yourself.  
If you are a client with a registered account, your personal information can be accessed by:

  * Our system administrators;
  * Our supporters when they (in order to provide support) need to get the information about the client accounts and access;
  * Regulators and government authorities in connection with our compliance procedures and obligations;
  * A purchaser or prospective purchaser of all or part of our assets or our business, and their professional advisers, in connection with the purchase;
  * A third party, in order to enforce or defend our rights, or to address financial or reputational risks;
  * Other recipients where we are authorised or required by law to do so.

## How do we store your personal information

We operate on web servers hosted in the US and in the Netherlands. Our hosting provider KnownHost LLC adheres to the EU/US “Privacy Shield”, ensuring that your data is securely stored and GDPR compliant. For more information on KnownHost’s privacy policy, please see here: [>KnownHost Privacy Policy](https://www.knownhost.com/privacy-policy.html).

## How long we keep your personal information

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations.

## What rights you have over your data

If you are a client with a registered account, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. If you have any questions, want to receive a copy of your stored data or have your data erased, please contact us at support@themenergy.com

## Information you make public or give to others

If you make your personal information available to other people, we can’t control or accept responsibility for the way they will use or manage that information. There are lots of ways that you may find yourself providing information to other people, like when you post a public message on a comment section, share information via social media, or make contact with another user via our Sites. Before making your information publicly available or giving your information to anyone else, think carefully. If giving information to another user via our Sites, ask them how they will handle your information. If you’re sharing information via another website, check the privacy policy for that site to understand its information management practices as this privacy policy will not apply.

## When we need to update this policy

We may need to change this policy from time to time in order to make sure it stays up to date with the latest legal requirements and any changes to our privacy management practices. When we do amend the policy, the changes will be effective straight away. We’ll usually publish information about changes to be made to this policy on our Sites – but please be aware that it is your responsibility to check in and make sure you keep up to date with any changes to this policy.

Last Updated: 25/05/2018

By continuing to use the site, you agree to the use of cookies. [more information](http://themeenergy.com/privacy-policy/)
